JING QUAN BUNG

DevOps Engineer / Cloud Engineer / Web API Engineer



DFTAILS

EMAIL

jqbung0318@gmail.com

SOCIAL LINKS

statusunknownthings.com github.com/jqbung0318 linkedin.com/in/jqbung-techies/

LANGUAGES

- Chinese*
- English*
- Bahasa Malaysia

EDUCATION

BSc Hons Software Engineering, University of Nottingham, Malaysia.

ACHIEVEMENTS

 AWS Certified Solution Architect – Associate

SKILLS

Cloud Service Platform

 AWS, GCP, Azure, Alibaba Cloud

Programming Language

 Python Django, NodeJS, GoLang, C Arduino

DevOps Tools

- Terraform, Jenkins, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes
- Proxmox, TrueNAS, pfSense SVN
- GitHub, JIRA, Trello, Linear

PROFILE

DevOps engineer with 2 years of field experience in managing deployments and maintenance of production services. Professionally utilizing Amazon Web Services to design, deploy, and maintain software solutions for productions. Strive for site-reliability engineering and automation role to assist in mission critical, time-sensitive products to enhance developing experience and end-user experience. 4 years in web API engineering with JavaScript and Python, but moving towards to GoLang & Rust for complex systems.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Intermediate Software Engineer, RedSquare Software Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur 2024 – Present

- Developer and maintainer of the DevOps cycles across multiple projects with GitHub Actions and Terraform.
- Well utilized AWS services to reduce delivery and service downtime.
- Core engineer in designing solution for vehicle management software.

Web Backend Engineer, Xamble Technologies Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur 2022 – 2023

- DevOps developer and maintainer for car listing websites for well-known local newspaper publisher.
- Successfully designed a core backend architecture on top of AWS and practice it among the developers in the team.
- Web backend developer for social marketing creator application with pay-out, chat & community integrations. Responsible for architecture design and DevOps tasks.

Software Architect, Pixel Pine Sdn Bhd

Kuala Lumpur 2019 –2022

- Collaborate with the BOD to analyse the business requirements ranging from in-house fleet management to external warehouse management projects.
- Highly involved in designing development tools for serverless based application on AWS. Successfully reduce up to 50% of time in blue-green deployment with proper unit testing.
- Productive and positive project team lead to guide team members to design, develop, and deploy IoT solutions ranges from agriculture, logistics, contact tracing, and individual tracking.